{
    "version": 2.0,
    "questions": [{
            "question": "Q1. Voltammetric technique described as a function of",
            "answers": {
                "a": "current, voltage",
                "b": "time, current",
                "c": "voltage, time",
                "d": "current, voltage, time"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "d"
        }, {
            "question": "Q2. In voltammetric technique",
            "answers": {
                "a": "applied voltage varies with current voltage",
                "b": "current & voltage varies with time",
                "c": "current is monitor when voltage is varied",
                "d": "current does not affect with varies voltage"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "c"
        }, {
            "question": "Q3. In cyclic voltammetry, the ferricyanide system undergoes:",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Acid–base reaction",
                "b": "Precipitation reaction",
                "c": "Reversible redox reaction",
                "d": "Thermal decomposition"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "c"
        }, {
            "question": "Q4. Voltammetric technique principle based on",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Ohm’s Law",
                "b": "Faraday’s Law",
                "c": "Kohlrausch Law",
                "d": "Kirchoff’s Law"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q5.  Potential in cyclic voltammetry is:",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Dependent variable",
                "b": "Independent variable",
                "c": "Constant",
                "d": "None of the above"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }, {
            "question": "Q6. Which of the following electrode is not used in voltammetry?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Working Electrode",
                "b": "Auxillary electrode",
                "c": "Reference electrode",
                "d": "Conducting electrode"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "d"
        }, {
            "question": "Q7. What are the common parameter involves in voltammetry?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Potential and current",
                "b": "Potential and resistance",
                "c": "Current and resistance",
                "d": "Current and electrodes"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q8. Which of the following is not involved in the migration of particles in solution during voltammetry?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Migration",
                "b": "Immigration",
                "c": "Convection",
                "d": "Diffusion"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }, {
            "question": "Q9. Which of the following electrodes are often used as counter or auxiliary electrode in voltammetry?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Calomel electrode",
                "b": "Carbon paste",
                "c": "Platinum wire",
                "d": "Mercury thin film"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "c"
        }, {
            "question": "Q10. Which of the following voltammetric techniques enhances the sensitivity through improving the faradaic current?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Differential pulse voltammetry",
                "b": "Square wave voltammetry",
                "c": "Cyclic voltammetry",
                "d": "Stripping voltammetry"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }
    ]
}
